COREY GRAD

DEVELOPER

- cgrad01.github.io
- **4** 914-263-8399
- **♀** New York, NY
- in /in/coreygrad
- cgrad01

After working as an analyst for a law firm, I learned that I bring value to a team from any role. I am a creative problem solver and enjoy thinking about and solving difficult problems. I love the attention to detail that programming requires, and get a great deal of gratification from the art of crafting a viable solution. I plan to gain expertise in my area of primary responsibility, and use my interpersonal skills to translate that expertise to non-developers.

Skills

LANGUAGES

Ruby

Javascript

HTML

CSS

SQL RSpec

Sass

FRAMEWORKS

Ruby on Rails

AngularJS

OTHER

jQuery

Git

Sinatra CircleCl

AIAX

ActiveRecord

Heroku

Bootstrap

Education

Dev Bootcamp

Villanova University B.S. Economics 2010

Projects

Juke

Juke is a playlist collaboration app built using Ruby on Rails, Javascript, and the Spotify API. Juke allows a host to invite guests to view, vote, and suggest songs on a playlist of the host's choosing. Those suggestions can be accepted by the host, and the playlist can be ordered according to vote count.

Managed team workflow and overall vision as Project Lead

Built ActionMailer functionality

Implemented modular structure to improve code readability

Designed and constructed voting feature

Refactored Spotify API call methods

Stack Overflow Clone

A recreation of the popular question and answer site for programmers.

AJAX page elements to improve user experience Designed and implemented schema using polymorphic associations Wrote tests, diagnosed and fixed bugs

Employment

American Business, Inc.

New York, NY

Operations Consultant

Jun 2015 to Sep 2015

 $Implemented\ process\ improvements\ for\ internal\ financial\ reporting\ and\ payables\ management$

Aligned marketing content across the firm

Revamped agent settlement process

Robbins Arroyo LLP

San Diego, CA Jun 2012 to Jun 2015

Lead Research Analyst

Managed team of seven analysts; first point of contact for every new potential cause of action

Identified new case opportunities; relied on for factual content of complaints; created three new case types

Developed deep understanding of regulatory liability in a wide variety of industries

Learned underlying fundamentals of industries including pharma, energy, financial services, and others

Amazel Software, Inc.

New York, NY

Research Assistant

May 2011 to Jun 2011

Conducted research for various sections of business plan for software start-up

Assisted creation of business plan and presentation material for potential investors and users

Professional Concessions Inc.

West Palm Beach, FL

Event Manager

Jan 2011 to Jun 2011

Planned event operations and managed events on-site

Analyzed sales post-event, performed basic accounting, responsible for cash management & banking

Awards

Robbins Arroyo · Employee of the Year

Dec 2014

Volunteering

Pan Mass Challenge · Rider/Team Member

Aug 2015

Rode 112 miles from Sturbridge, MA to Bourne, MA in support of Dana Farber Cancer Research Institute. My team, Four Brothers, raised over \$65,000 for cancer research in memory of our loved ones.